







Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section | Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

An experienced software consultancy proprietor having more than 14 years of industry experience, skills predominantly revolving around C#.NET. I've strong experience in all phases of software development life cycle. I have completed PMP(Project management professionals) training and Price2 foundation and Practitioner certification. As a strong in areas like C#,ASP.NET, SQL server, UML,WCF,NUnit and always taken initiative to use such technologies, in successful implementation of projects. I am running my own software consultancy Trupti Solutions and working as a consultant for client based in London

Work Experience

Trupti Solutions as Consultant

Jun 2010 to Till Date

Project Title: Camelot Europe Website (Internet site for MNC)

Client: Camelot Property Management (UK)

Employer: Trupti Solutions

Duration: March 2016 - Till Date (India)

Role: Project Manager Project Synopsis:

Camelot Europe website is implemented in PHP and Drupal. It is content based website for 8 countries in Europe and UK. Client business is handle by this website. Google SEO, Analytics, Advertisement etc tools were used. REST service is developed in order to communicate with different platform of Intranet website.

Responsibilities:

- Resource allocation.
- Project Co-Ordination.
- * Solution design for enhancements.
- * Resource recruitment
- Time estimation and Prioritization of tasks.
- Making Timesheet and Generating invoices.

Project Title: TruptiSolutions (Internet site for company)

Client: Camelot Property Management (UK)

Employer: Trupti Solutions
Duration: August 2010

Role: Project Manager. (Analyst programmer, Design and implementation of company website)

Project Synopsis:

Trupti Solutions is an India based software consultancy to provide customized professional software solutions using

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

enormous experience in software development. This website is developed for the growth of Trupti solutions as well as to establish an identitty in the international market.

Responsibilities:

- Managing Trupti Solutions and Designed, Developed and launched www.truptisolutions.com
- Analysis of the requirements from client.
- Design the solution so that there will be minimum changes in the current system and new design can easily accommodate future enhancements
- Design using HTML, ASP .NET, CSS, Adobe Photoshop, Flex, Adobe Flash Builder, JQuery, Action script
- Back end coding using C#
- Unit testing and deployment on server.

Technologies Used: VS2008, SQL server 2008, Dynamsoft SCM Anywhere Hosted Client for scource control. SSRS

Camelot Property Management as Project Architect and Project Manager Jan 2010 to Jun 2010

Role: Project Architect and Project Manager. (Analyst Programmer, Conducted interview of candidates, trained them in C#, ASP .NET and SQL server)

Project Synopsis:

Camelot Property management has branches all over the Europe. This company manages properties and takes care of them by placing guardians in the property. I am implementing intranet website of this company. I was working for this company in UK and now arrived in India and working for them from India. As a part of growing IT team, I have recruited 2 candidates and trained them on Microsoft technologies such as C#, ASP. NET and SQL server.

Responsibilities:

- Analysis of the requirements
- Design the solution so that there will be minimum changes in the current system and new design can easily accommodate future enhancements.
- Front end design using HTML, ASP .NET, CSS, JQuery.
- Back end coding using C#,Linq
 Writing store procedures and UDF in SQL server 2008.
- Unit testing and deployment on test server.
- Shortlisting candidates, Interviewing and Training them.
- Encouraging them for Microsoft certification exams.
- Assigning tasks to new candidates, helping them in design, implementation and deployment.
- Taken candidates to Onsite for 2 months in London. Handled responsibilities of their Visa processing etc. Technologies Used: VS2008, SQL server 2008, Dynamsoft SCMAnywhere Hosted Client for scource control SSRS

Capgemini as Analyst Programmer

Aug 2009 to Dec 2009

Project Synopsis:

Capgemini is software consulting company with more than 80,000 employees all over the world. It is a Learning Skill Counsel's (LSC) project for UK government. It consists of Mcrosoft Content Management Server (MCMS) to work with all LSC websites along with CAS. This site provides online courses as well as job assistance with all types of job profiles. My role was quite unique in this project because I was replaced with one contractor and senior developer. Also one Team lead was only 25% on this project. So I was handling responsibilities of Team lead as well as senior and junior developer. I was responsible for complete project life cycle.

Responsibilities:

- Analysis of the specifications provided by the clients.

 Implemented change request using MCMS API, Web form, C#, ASP .NET
- Implemented WCF service which is acting as a wrapper for third party search engine called Coveo.
- Development and enhancement of the project using Agile methodology
- Functional testing on different web browsers and creating MSI.
- Code check in, creating labels and creating hand over to deployment document.
- Helping deployment team in installing components on server.
- Interacting with testing team to complete SIT, UAT and LIVE.
- Analysing defects and solving them guickly so that we can proceed to the next phase.

Technologies Used: MCMS, CCS, ASP,C# .Net 3.5 and .NET 3.0, SQL Server 2008, Windows platform, Visual Studio 2008, WCF, Clearcase, CleareQuest.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Sinhagad Institute of Technology, Pune in 2005

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
C#, ASP .NET, HTML, CSS, XML		
UML, C++, Action script, JQuery		
.NET 2.0 to .NET 4.5, WCF, EF		
ADO.NET, SQL Server , AWS, Salesforce		
ClearCase, CVS, ClearQuest, Github		
Windows , Ubuntu , Photoshop		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.